<main langID='1'>
  <chapter id='1'>
    <chaptername>Introduction to iPod Shuffle</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>INTRODUCTION TO iPod SHUFFLE</b> </p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>Hello!!! I'm Amy... <br><br>This is Apple's display-less and smallest iPod - the new 2nd generation 1GB iPod Shuffle.<br><br>A 2GB model is also available. <br><br>The 1 GB model holds up to 16 hours of music, while the 2 GB model stores up to 32 hours of music.<br><br>Apple introduced this matchbox-sized, badge-like digital music player in early 2005.<br><br>This breakthrough gadget was designed around iPod's legendary shuffle feature.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='2'>
    <chaptername>System Requirements for Windows and Mac</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>PRE... REQUISITES<br><br>Your computer specification</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>To use your iPod shuffle, you require a few hardware and software settings for your computer.<br><br>If you are a Mac user, your Mac computer should have:<br><br><ul><li>An Intel, PowerPC G5, G4, or G3 processor with Mac OS X version 10.4.8 or later</li><li>A minimum of 512 MB RAM</li><li>At least 200MB of available disk space.</li><li>And a USB 2.0 port</li></ul><br><br>If you are a Windows user, make sure your PC has:<br><br><ul><li>1GHz Intel or AMD processor with Windows Vista or Windows XP Home or Professional with Service Pack 2 or later</li><li>a minimum of 512 MB RAM.</li><li>at least 200MB of available disk space</li><li>and a USB 2.0 port</li></ul><br><br>Additionally, your computer - whether it is a Mac or a Windows PC - must have:<br><br><ul><li>iTunes version 7.4 or later</li><li>And Apple QuickTime player version 7.5.5 or later.</li></ul><br><br>The iTunes Store is a vital feature of iTunes.<br><br>To access the iTunes Store and other online resources, you must have an Internet connection - preferably from a broadband service provider.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='3'>
    <chaptername>Switches and controls</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>KNOW YOUR iPod SHUFFLE</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>(1) Open the pack and you find a hard, transparent plastic box.<br><br><ul><li>Lift the lid.</li><li>The Shuffle is attached to a hard plastic sheet.</li><li>Hold the gadget and lift it gently, but firmly, upward - and detach the iPod Shuffle unit from the Plastic sheet.</li><li>The accessories you find inside are:</li><ul><li>1.A multilingual quick guide instructional manual.</li><li>2.Earphones</li><li>3.A dock with a USB connector. </li></ul></ul><br><br>(2) Let us check the gadget.<br><br><ul><li>The one port, on the top left of the iPod Shuffle, is an input-output port. This is used for your earphones, for charging the battery and also for data transfer.</li><li>On the top right, there is a tiny status light.</li><li>When you turn the gadget around, you see that the entire rear portion of the iPod Shuffle is, in fact, a clip. If you press the right edge, the clip jaw opens.</li><li>	Under the clip you have the iPod serial number specific to your Shuffle. It will come in handy when you register your iPod Shuffle or when your iPod needs servicing.</li><li>At the bottom there are 2 sliding switches. </li><li>The one on the left is the Shuffle switch and it carries two symbols - shuffle and repeat. Slide the switch to the left to shuffle, and to the right to repeat.</li><li>The switch on the right is the Power switch. Slide this to the right to turn on your iPod Shuffle. A green bar then becomes visible underneath.</li><li>To turn off the iPod Shuffle, slide the switch to OFF and the green bar disappears.</li><li>The second status light is next to the Power switch.</li><li>On the front face of the iPod Shuffle, there is a circular control pad to control playback.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='4'>
    <chaptername>Specifitactions and Operating Conditions</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>TECHNICAL SPECIFICATIONS OF iPod SHUFFLE</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>Your iPod shuffle, whether it's 1 GB or 2 GB, weighs 15.6 grams or 0.55 ounce.<br><br>It is 1.07 inches (or 27.3 mm) high, 1.62 inches (or 41.2 mm) wide and, with its clip, 0.41 inch (or 10.5 mm) deep.<br><br>Your Shuffle will be comfortably operational within a temperature range of 32 to 95 degrees Fahrenheit or 0 to 35 degrees Centigrade.<br><br>It will function properly, without the problem of condensation, in relative humidity of 5% to 95%.<br><br>The gadget will work comfortably up to an altitude of 10,000 feet or 3000 meters.<br><br>In short, your iPod Shuffle will operate almost anywhere</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='5'>
    <chaptername>What can it do - listen to music, podcasts, audio books or use as external storage device</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>WHAT CAN YOU DO WITH YOUR iPod SHUFFLE?</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>You can use your iPod Shuffle for listening to songs or music.<br><br>You can listen to Podcasts.<br><br>You can listen to audiobooks.<br><br>You can also use your iPod Shuffle as an external portable drive, or storage device, to store data files.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='6'>
    <chaptername>How to download and Install the latest iTunes and Quicktime</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>iTUNES & QUICKTIME</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>To use the iPod Shuffle, install the latest version of iTunes and Apple QuickTime Player software.<br><br>iTunes is the digital media player application-cum-online resource access software, introduced by Apple to synchronize music, audiobooks, and podcasts with your iPod shuffle.<br><br>This application allows all iPod compatible audio files to be transferred from your computer to your iPod Shuffle.<br><br>QuickTime Player is another media player application introduced by Apple.<br><br><p class='headingText'><b>Installation:</b></p><br><br>iTunes and QuickTime Player Software are available as free downloads for Mac OS X, Windows Vista, and Windows XP from the Apple website.<br><br>To confirm the compatibility of the iTunes version with your computer's Operating System, check the Apple website.<br><br>To install these software :<ul><li>Open the website <a href="www.apple.com">www.apple.com</a> on your Internet web browser.</li><li>Go to the Downloads option at the top of the page.</li><li>Click on the Download button inside the iTunes box.</li><li>Once downloading is over, an iTunes Setup icon appears in the download destination.</li><li> Double click this icon to start the installation process.</li><li>A welcome screen appears. It informs you that the installer will install iTunes and QuickTime Player one by one.</li><li>Click on Next.</li><li>Read the license agreement carefully, accept the terms and click on Next.</li><li>If you wish to change the Destination Folder of your installation, click on Change and select the new destination.</li><li>Click on Install.</li><li>The status screen shows the progress of the software installation.</li><li>Once the installation is over, "Congratulations" screen appears.</li><li>Deselect Open iTunes after the installer exits, and click on Finish.</li><li>iTunes and Apple QuickTime Player are now installed on your computer.</li></ul> <br><br>You must restart your computer to be able to use iTunes.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='7'>
    <chaptername>How to find your way around the iTunes Player and iTunes Store</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>INTERFACE OF iTUNES</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>iTunes has two parts, iTunes Player and iTunes Store.<br><br>The iTunes interface is divided into six areas.<br><br><ol><li>The Transport and view controls area at the top.</li><li>The Source List area on the left.</li><li>The Cover art or Album art area at the bottom left.</li><li>The Cover Flow display area towards the upper middle.</li><li>The Track List area at the bottom.</li><li>The Status bar and controls area - also at the bottom.</li></ol><br><br>The Transport and view controls area shows you the iTunes menu bar<br><br><ul><li>From left to right, there are the Reverse, Play/Pause and Forward buttons to control playback on iTunes.</li><li>	Besides this, there is the mute button, the volume increase or decrease slider and the maximum volume button.</li><li>Current playing track information - like track title, artist, album, elapsed time of play and time remaining - appears at the centre.</li><li>Click on the right arrow button on the left side - and the iTunes graphics equalizer appears.</li><li>Click the button again to see track information.</li><li>Three view buttons let you choose the program view options.</li><li>And the Search box at the right lets you search for an item in your iTunes library.</li></ul><br><br>The Source List area has 3 parts.<br><br><ul><li>iTunes Library, which gives you access to media files stored on your computer.</li><li>iTunes Store, which gives you access to the online iTunes store.</li><li>And Playlists, which shows all the playlists that you have created.</li></ul><br><br>The Cover art or Album art area is optional.<br><br><ul><li>It displays the cover artwork of the currently selected video or audio track.</li><li>Click on the Down Arrow or Hide Artwork button to hide the artwork and make more space for the Source List area.</li><li>Click on the Up Arrow or Show Artwork button to show the album artwork.</li></ul><br><br><ul><li>Click on the Cover Flow view button at the top.</li><li>The album covers will appear for all the tracks in the iTunes library.</li><li>You can navigate through the Cover Flow view by scrolling horizontally.</li><li>Optionally, you can use the Left Arrow or Right Arrow keys to scroll.</li></ul><br><br>The Track list area displays the content and track information of the selected item in the Source List area.<br><br><ul><li>Click on other View buttons to see the full screen.</li></ul><br><br>The Status bar and controls area displays<br><br><ul><li>The total no. of audio or video tracks, the total playback time, and the disk space used to store all the tracks for the selected item in the iTunes Library.</li></ul><br><br>You will find a few other controls here.<br><br><ul><li>Click once on the (+) button to create a new playlist in iTunes.</li><li>Click once on the Shuffle mode button, to switch to a random play order in iTunes. The button turns blue.</li><li>Click again on this button for sequential play in iTunes. The Shuffle mode is off.</li><li>Click once on the Repeat button to repeat a playlist. The button turns blue.</li><li>Click again on the Repeat button to repeat a single item.</li><li>Click again to turn off Repeat mode.</li></ul><br><br>To access iTunes Store, you must connect to the Internet.<br><br><ul><li>Click on iTunes Store.</li><li>An "Accessing iTunes Store" message will appear. </li><li>At the top of the iTunes Store window, you will find 3 buttons.</li><li>Click on the right arrow button to go forward to the next iTunes Store window.</li><li>Click on the left arrow button to go back to the previous iTunes Store window.</li><li>Click on the home button to go back directly to the iTunes Store home page.</li><li>You will find the categories available under iTunes Store at the left.</li><li>Scroll vertically; you will see a series of resource links in the iTunes Store.</li><li>Say, you're in the Music category under the New Release link.</li><li>Click on the page button to access the next page content.</li><li>Click on the Movies tab. </li><li>The album or cover artwork view... called the Cover Flow view... will open up.</li><li>Scroll to navigate thru new movie releases.</li><li>At the bottom, choose a country from the pop-up menu.</li><li>The national flag appears for the country you've set.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='8'>
    <chaptername>How to Connect to your computer</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>CONNECT THE STUFFLE TO YOUR COMPUTER</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>We connect the iPod Shuffle to the computer for two purposes - charging, and loading music and data.<br><br>To connect the Shuffle to your computer:<br><br><ul><li>Put your iPod Shuffle on the dock by inserting the jack in the input-output port.</li><li>Plug in the dock USB connector into a USB 2.0 port of your computer.</li><li>iTunes opens up automatically.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'><b>DISCONNECTING iPod SHUFFLE FROM YOUR COMPUTER</b></p><br><br>Remember, if you see the "Do not disconnect" message in iTunes, or if the status light on iPod shuffle is blinking orange, don't try to disconnect it.<br><br>You must eject iPod shuffle before disconnecting or detaching it. Otherwise, you could damage files on the iPod shuffle.<br><br>1) To disconnect your Shuffle:<br><br><ul><li>Make sure the "iPod sync is complete" message appears in iTunes.</li><li>Click the Eject button next to iPod shuffle in the iTunes Source Pane.</li><li>Now safely disconnect or detach the iPod shuffle from your computer.</li><li>You can now also remove it from the dock.</li></ul><br><br>(2) There is another way to disconnect your iPod Shuffle.<br><br>If you're using a Mac:<ul><li>Eject iPod shuffle by dragging the iPod shuffle icon on the desktop to Trash.</li><li>Now, disconnect the iPod shuffle from your computer.</li></ul><br><br>If you're using a Windows PC,<ul><li>Eject iPod shuffle by clicking the Safely Remove Hardware icon in the Windows system tray.</li><li>A message box appears.</li><li>Select iPod shuffle. Click on Stop.</li><li>You will see a message which says: Safe to remove hardware.</li><li>Now, disconnect the iPod shuffle from your computer.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='9'>
    <chaptername>How to charge the iPod Shuffle</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>HOW TO CHARGE THE iPod SHUFFLE</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>There is a built-in rechargeable lithium polymer battery inside your iPod Shuffle - and it takes around four hours to charge it fully.<br><br>Remember, this battery cannot be accessed by the user. So, do not try to disassemble your iPod Shuffle.<br><br>The Shuffle needs to be charged after every twelve hours of use.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Charging through your computer</p><br><br>To charge the battery through your computer<br><br><ul><li>Make sure your computer is switched on, and not in sleep mode.</li><li>Place your iPod Shuffle in the dock.</li><li>Plug in the dock USB connector to the USB 2.0 port of your computer - and charging starts.</li><li>While the battery is charging, the status light in your iPod shuffle turns amber.</li><li>When the battery is fully charged, the light turns green.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Charging the Battery through iPod USBPower Adapter</p><br><br>If you are not using your computer for charging your iPod Shuffle, you can use an iPod USB Power Adapter.<br><br>To do this:<br><br><ul><li>Place your iPod shuffle in the dock.</li><li>Assemble the iPod USB Power Adapter - by joining the AC plug adapter to the power adapter.</li><li>Plug in the USB connector of the iPod shuffle dock to the power adapter.</li><li>Plug in the power adapter to a working electrical outlet - and charging starts.</li><li>Check if the battery status light turns amber. When fully charged, the status light turns green.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='10'>
    <chaptername>How to find the Battery Status</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>THE BATTERY STATUS</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>Before playing your iPod Shuffle, you must check its battery status.<br><br>Two status lights "one on the top, and the other at the bottom" let you know the status.<br><br><ul><li>Slide the switch to turn on your Shuffle.</li><li>If the indicator is green, it means the battery is charged.</li><li>If it is amber, the battery charge is low.</li><li>And if the status light is red, your battery charge is almost zero - and you need to charge your iPod Shuffle immediately.</li><li>Remember, if the status light is blinking amber, don't try to detach or disconnect your shuffle from the dock.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Check the battery status while the Shuffle is playing</p><br><br>When you're listening to your iPod Shuffle, you can check the current battery status without interrupting audio playback.<br><br><ul><li>Turn off the iPod shuffle and, then, turn it on immediately. You have to do this very fast or the music will stop.</li><li>The status light indicates the battery status.</li></ul><br><br>The iPod shuffle battery is 80-percent charged in about two hours, and fully charged in about four hours.When your Shuffle is fully charged, it can play up to 12 hours of audio.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='11'>
    <chaptername>How to Sync with iTunes</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>SYNC YOUR iPod SHUFFLE WITH iTUNES</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>To synchronize your iPod Shuffle with your computer for the first time:<br><br><ul><li>Connect the iPod shuffle to your computer.</li><li>iTunes opens automatically.</li></ul><br><br>An iPod Setup Assistant screen appears.<br><br><ul><li>The Setup Assistant helps you configure your iPod shuffle and sync it with your iTunes library.</li><li>You can give a name to your iPod Shuffle. Type the name in the input box.</li><li>You also get an offer to "Automatically choose songs for my iPod".</li><li>You may select this option only if you want iTunes to fill your iPod with songs from the library automatically.</li><li>Let us deselect this option for now.</li><li>Click Done.</li><li>Check the message in iTunes. Your iPod Shuffle is now synchronized with the iTunes library.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='12'>
    <chaptername>How to Import audio into iTunes Library</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>IMPORTING AUDIO INTO iTUNES LIBRARY</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>You can import music from audio CDs into iTunes.<br><br>You can also add music - and other audio - already existing on your computer, to iTunes.<br><br>And in the iTunes Store, you can buy music and audiobooks - or subscribe to podcasts - and download these into your iTunes Library.<br><br>To import Audio CD tracks into your iPod Shuffle<br><br><ul><li>Open iTunes.</li><li>Insert an audio CD into your computer.</li><li>If a message appears, asking whether you wish to import the CD, click No for now.</li><li>The CD title appears under Devices in the iTunes Source list.</li><li>Click on the title - the tracks will be displayed in the Contents window.</li><li>Deselect any song you don't want to import from the CD.</li><li>Now, click the Import CD button at the bottom right of the iTunes window.</li><li>The import starts - and the display area at the top of the iTunes window shows the time required to import each song.</li><li>An orange circular icon appears next to a track title while it is being imported.</li><li>This changes to a green check mark when the track is fully imported into the iTunes Library.</li><li>Once importing is over, all the tracks appear under Music in the iTunes Library.</li><li>Click the Eject button to retrieve your CD.</li><li>Double click on any track name and listen to the track</li><li>To stop playing, click on the iTunes Player's Play / Pause button or simply press the spacebar.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Include music information</p><br><br>To manually enter song titles, other information and comments in your iTunes library<br><br><ul><li>Select the track in iTunes library.</li><li>Select File and then Get Info.</li><li>Click on the Info tab.</li><li>Enter the song information.</li><li>Click Next to enter information for the next track.</li><li>Click OK when you finish.</li><li>The new information now appears in the iTunes Library.</li></ul><br><br>If you don't see the track name in the Contents window, iTunes can get this for you if the track is available over the Internet, when you connect to the Internet next time.<br><br>To do this <br><br><ul><li>Select the track in the iTunes Library.</li><li>Go to the Advanced menu.</li><li>Select Get CD Track Names.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Audio files from your computer into iTunes</p><br><br>You can add digital music files – like AAC, MP3, WAV, AA or AIFF files - from your computer hard disk to the iTunes library<br><br>To do this<br><br><ul><li>Make sure iTunes is open.</li><li>Select File and, then, Add File to Library.</li><li>Go to the folder or disk containing the audio files.</li><li>Press down the Shift key on a Windows PC keyboard - or Command key on a Mac computer keyboard - while selecting the songs.</li><li>Click Open.</li><li>The songs are added to the Library.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='13'>
    <chaptername>How to Load music manually</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>LOADING MUSIC ONTO iPod SHUFFLE MANUALLY</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>You can load songs, music tracks and playlists onto your iPod shuffle manually.<br><br>To do this<br><br><ul><li>Make sure your iPod Shuffle is connected to the computer.</li><li>In iTunes, go to Library and click on Music.</li><li>Select your song.</li><li>Press down the Shift key on your keyboard, to select multiple songs at a time.</li><li>Drag the selection to the iPod shuffle icon in the Source List.</li><li>While the music is being transferred, a message appears saying "Syncing iPod. Do not disconnect".</li><li>Once transfer is complete, the message changes to 'iPod sync is complete'.</li><li>You can also select a playlist under PLAYLISTS in the Source List.</li><li>The songs or music tracks in the playlist appear in the Contents window</li><li>Drag the playlist onto the iPod Shuffle icon in the Source List.</li><li>The playlist's songs or music tracks are transferred to your Shuffle.</li><li>You must eject your Shuffle before detaching from the computer.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='14'>
    <chaptername>How to Play music using Circular Control Panel and various Playback Modese  - Shuffle and Repeat</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>PLAYING MUSIC</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>To play music on your iPod Shuffle<br><br><ul><li>Plug the earphones jack into the iPod shuffle.</li><li>Fit the earphones into your ears. The letters L and R - for your left and right ears respectively - are indicated clearly on the two earphones.</li><li>Turn on your iPod Shuffle.</li></ul><br><br>Circular Control Pad<br><br><ul><li>Now, press Play/Pause on the circular control pad.</li><li>Control your Shuffle's volume with the + and the - buttons.</li><li>Press the Next or Forward button once, to skip to the next audio track.</li><li>Press the Previous or Rewind button once to return to the beginning of the current track.</li><li>Press and hold the Next or Forward button to fast-forward through the current track.</li><li>Press and hold the Previous or Rewind button to rewind through the current track.</li><li>Press the Previous or Rewind button twice to skip back to the previous audio track.</li></ul><br><br>Playing modes<br><br>Your iPod Shuffle has two modes - shuffle and repeat - to play audio track<br><br><ul><li>To play tracks in shuffle mode, which means in random order, slide the shuffle switch left to the shuffle mode.</li><li>To reshuffle songs, press Play/Pause three times quickly.</li><li>To play tracks in the order they were copied, slide the shuffle switch right to the repeat mode.</li><li>To return to the first song, press the Play / Pause button three times quickly, within a second.</li><li>To turn off your Shuffle, press the Play/Pause button once to stop playback. Then, slide the Power switch to OFF.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='15'>
    <chaptername>How to Remove music or other items from iPod Shuffle</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>REMOVING MUSIC OR OTHER ITEMS FROM iPod SHUFFLE</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>You can remove audio tracks from your iPod Shuffle only through iTunes.<br><br>To remove a song or other item from iPod shuffle<br><br><ul><li>Make sure iTunes is open.</li><li>Select iPod Shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Select an audio track in the contents window.</li><li>Press the Delete key on your keyboard.</li><li>A message appears, asking you to confirm the deletion. Click Remove</li><li>You now see a "Syncing iPod'. Do not disconnect" message.</li><li>Once the deletion is complete, the message changes to 'iPod sync is complete'. </li><li>You must eject your Shuffle before detaching from the computer.</li></ul><br><br>Remember, removing a track from the iPod shuffle does not delete it from your iTunes library.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='16'>
    <chaptername>How to Create and access your  iTunes Store account using  your Apple ID or your AOL account</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>ACCESS YOUR ONLINE ACCOUNT, iTUNES STORE ACCOUNT OR APPLE ID</b> </p><br><br> <p class='bodyText'>iTunes Store, is the huge online resource of music and songs, albums, audiobooks, podcasts and videos, from where you can purchase and download content for your iPod.<br><br>Some downloads are free.<br><br>You can sign up in iTunes to purchase music online from the iTunes Store.<br><br>To sign up:<br><br><ul><li>Connect to the Internet.</li><li>Go to the menu bar.</li><li>Select Store and Create Account.</li><li>A screen will appear. It says, Welcome to the iTunes Store. </li><li>Click on Continue.</li><li>Read the Terms of Service of the iTunes Store carefully. Check the box to agree with the terms and conditions.</li><li>Click on Continue.</li><li>A screen will appear. It says: Create iTunes Store Account (Apple ID).</li><li>Enter the required information in the input box to set up an Apple account.</li><li>Click on continue.</li><li>Remember, if you already have a PayPal account, you can use that as your payment method when you enter your credit card information.</li></ul><br><br>After your new iTunes Store account is created, you can sign out.<br><br><ul><li>Click on the Sign Out button.</li></ul><br><br>You now have an iTunes Store account. So from now on, to access iTunes Store:<br><br><ul><li>Simply choose Store.</li><li>Click on Sign In.</li><li>Enter your Apple ID and password.</li><li>Click on the Sign In button.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'><b>AOL Account</b> </p><br><br>You can also use your AOL account, if you have one, for iTunes Store purchases.<br><br>To access this account:<br><br><ul><li>Click on Store and Sign In.</li><li>Click on the AOL icon.</li><li>Enter your AOL Screen name and password.</li><li>Click on the Sign In button to access your iTunes Store Account.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='17'>
    <chaptername>How to Search for music and using Quick links and Power search</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>SEARCHING MUSIC</b> </p><br><br> <p class='bodyText'>You can get your favorite songs and music through iTunes Store.<br><br>Searching the iTunes Store<br><br>To find the album, song, or artist you’re looking for:<br><br><ul><li>Make sure you are connected to the Internet.</li><li>Open iTunes and click iTunes Store in the Source List.</li><li>You will see a message; "Accessing iTunes Store".</li><li>The iTunes Store home window will appear.</li><li>Choose a music genre from the Genre pop-up menu on the left.</li><li>The names of tracks under that genre are displayed on the right.</li><li>To narrow your search, type any track information in the search field at the top right of the screen.</li><li>Press Enter on your keyboard.</li><li>The search result will appear in the iTunes Store Window</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Browsing the iTunes Store using Quick Links </p><br><br>You can browse in the main iTunes Store window.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Click on Browse under QUICK LINKS on the right side.</li><li>Select Music under iTunes Store.</li><li>Select a genre within the Genre window on the right.</li><li>A subgenre list will appear.</li><li>Select a subgenre.</li><li>Names of artists under the selected subgenre will appear in the Artist window.</li><li>Select an artist’s name.</li><li>Available album names will appear inside the Album window.</li><li>Select an album.</li><li>You will find Track details in the lower half of the iTunes Store window.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Power Search </p><br><br>You can set a combination of criteria to narrow your search for music and songs from the iTunes Store.<br><br>This search method is called Power Search.<br><br>To use this feature of iTunes Store,<br><br><ul><li>Make sure iTunes Store is open.</li><li>Click on Power Search under QUICK LINKS on the right.</li><li>The Power Search window opens.</li><li>Select Music from the Power Search pop-up menu on the left.</li><li>Select a genre from the Genre pop-up menu on the right.</li><li>You have four input boxes, Artist, Composer, Song and Album.</li><li>Enter the appropriate text in the input boxes.</li><li>Click on the Search button.</li><li>The search result will appear in the lower half of the iTunes Store window.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='18'>
    <chaptername>How to buy and dowload a Song or Album online</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>SONG OR ALBUM - BUYING ONLINE TO DOWNLOAD</b> </p><br><br> <p class='bodyText'>Once you finish searching the iTunes Store, preview the item you wish to purchase.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Double-click the song, or other item, in iTunes.</li><li>Listen to a preview.</li></ul><br><br>Now, purchase the item.<br><br>Apple offers two methods for purchasing online from iTunes Store.<br><br>1. 1-Click.<br><br>2. Shopping Cart.<br><br>You can use either of these for your online shopping.<br><br>The default purchasing option is 1-Click.<br><br>To purchase using the1-Click method;<br><br><ul><li>Sign-up to create your new iTunes Store account, if you do not have one.</li><li>Or sign-in to your account, if you already have an iTunes or AOL account.</li><li>Click Buy Song or Buy Album.</li><li>The purchase is charged to the credit card listed in your iTunes Store account, i.e. Apple account or AOL account – and download to your iTunes library starts automatically.</li><li>Once download is complete – go to Music under Library. You will see the purchased track.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='19'>
    <chaptername>How to find Audio podcasts,  download free ones to the iTunes library, subscribe, unsubscribe and transfer to your shuffle</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>PODCASTS</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>A podcast is simply a digital media file of a radio-style program, distributed over the Internet, typically in MP3 format.<br><br>Internet radio, another form of audio program, streams live content over the Internet in real time. To listen to it, you have to be connected to the Internet.<br><br>But Podcasts don’t operate in real time, they are pre-recorded programs.<br><br>You download podcasts from the Internet into iTunes on your computer. You then play these podcasts – on your computer or your iPod – even when you're not connected to the Internet.<br><br>Most podcasts are free in iTunes Store.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Find Audio podcasts </p><br><br>Remember, podcasts are not available in the iTunes Store for some countries.<br><br>To browse for podcasts in iTunes;<br><br><ul><li>Open iTunes.</li><li>Select iTunes Store under STORE. The iTunes Store contents appear.</li><li>Click the Podcasts link.</li><li>A message appears. It says, "Accessing iTunes Store".</li><li>While the Store is being accessed, the iTunes progress bar moves.</li><li>The iTunes Store page then opens – and the available podcasts appear.</li></ul><br><br>Though iTunes Store offers thousands of free podcasts, you still find podcasts available for download on other websites.<br><br>Apple lets you manage these podcasts through iTunes.<br><br>Some of these sites are:<br><br><ul><li>www.digitalpodcast.com</li><li>www.podcastalley.com</li><li>www.podcasting-station.com</li><li>www.podcastingnews.com</li><li>www.podfeed.net</li></ul><br><br> <p class='headingText'>Download free audio podcasts into iTunes Library</p><br><br>You can download free Audio Podcasts from iTunes store onto your iPod Shuffle.<br><br>To download;<br><br><ul><li>Make sure iTunes Store is open.</li><li>Click on Audio Podcasts</li><li>The available audio podcasts will appear on the screen.</li><li>On the right, you will find Top Audio Podcasts.</li><li>And on the left, you will find the podcast categories.</li><li>To select a podcast of your choice, click on the podcast name.</li><li>The podcast window will open.</li><li>At the top, there is a home button of iTunes Store.</li><li>Beside this the current podcast category, source and name appear.</li><li>The Free tag indicates that it’s a podcast free for download into your iTunes Library.</li><li>Scroll horizontally if required and select a podcast episode.</li><li>Click Get Episode.</li><li>You will find a small rotating icon beside Downloads, under STORE.</li><li>This indicates the podcast episode is getting downloaded.</li><li>Click Downloads</li><li>The status bar shows the progress of downloading, the size of the podcast file and the time remaining for download to complete.</li></ul><br><br> <p class='headingText'>Playing your podcast in iTunes</p><br><br>When the download is complete, you can play the podcast in iTunes.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Click Podcast under LIBRARY.</li><li>You will find the downloaded podcasts.</li><li>Select an episode.</li><li>Click the Play button.</li><li>The podcast starts playing.</li></ul><br><br> <p class='headingText'>Subscribe or unsubscribe the podcast in iTunes</p><br><br>Subscribe:<br><br>You can subscribe to a podcast – and get all its available and forthcoming episodes.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Make sure Podcast is selected under LIBRARY in iTunes.</li><li>Click the right arrow button. The podcast area will expand to display the downloaded episodes.</li><li>Click the Subscribe button beside the podcast name.</li><li>You will find all the available episodes of that podcast.</li><li>If you further want to download another episode, click the Get button.</li><li>Download starts.</li><li>For the forthcoming episodes of that podcast, click on Settings.</li><li>A window will appear.</li><li>To set the downloading options;<ol><li>1.You can set how often iTunes should check for new episodes.</li><li>2.You can set conditions for downloading new episodes.</li><li>3.You can set the number of episodes iTunes should retain.</li></ol></li><li>Once the options are set, click OK.</li><li>So, when you connect to the Internet next, the new episodes of that podcast will be downloaded automatically into your iTunes Library.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Unsubscribe </p><br><br>If you don’t want to download any other episode of a podcast, you can unsubscribe it.<br><br>To unsubscribe a podcast;<br><br><ul><li>Go to Podcast under LIBRARY in iTunes.</li><li>Click the Unsubscribe button at the bottom.</li><li>The remaining episodes will disappear from the contents window.</li><li>The podcast is successfully unsubscribed.</li></ul><br><br> <p class='headingText'>Transferring the podcasts to your Shuffle</p><br><br>If you want to load podcasts onto your iPod shuffle, you must load them manually.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Connect your iPod Shuffle to the computer.</li><li>ITunes opens automatically.</li><li>Click on Podcasts in iTunes Library and the podcasts content of your library will appear.</li><li>Select a podcast.</li><li>Press down the Shift key and select multiple podcasts.</li><li>Drag the selection to the iPod Shuffle icon in the Source List.</li><li>You will see the message: "iPod is syncing...".</li><li>Wait till the message "iPod sync is complete" appears</li><li>Click on iPod Shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>The podcasts have been loaded onto your Shuffle.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='20'>
    <chaptername>How to find and purchase an Audio book from the iTunes store and Audible.com, tranfer to and play them on your shuffle</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>AUDIOBOOKS</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>Have you ever thought of listening to your favourite bestseller while you travel...!<br><br>Yes! It’s now possible with your iPod shuffle.<br><br>Many books have verbal versions – or audiobook versions – available now.<br><br>An audiobook is now available on the Internet in downloadable digital audio file formats like MP3, WMA, AA etc.<br><br>The most common sources of Audiobooks are iTunes Store and www.audible.com<br><br>Load these audiobooks onto your iPod shuffle, and hear them in the same way as you hear music.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Find the audiobook</p><br><br>iTunes has many offerings in its Audiobooks area, even current bestsellers.<br><br>To find an audiobook:<ul><li>Go to iTunes Store.</li><li>Click on Audiobooks.</li><li>Double-click on an Audiobook of your choice to listen to a preview.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Purchase audiobook from iTunes Store</p><br><br><ul><li>Sign-up to create your new iTunes Store account, if you do not have one.</li><li>Or sign-in to your account, if you already have an iTunes or AOL account.</li><li>Go to iTunes Store – and, then, Audiobooks.</li><li>Click any title you like.</li><li>Click on Buy Book.</li><li>The purchase is charged to the credit card listed in your iTunes Store account, i.e. Apple account or AOL account – and download to your iTunes library starts automatically.</li><li>Once download is complete – go to Audiobooks under Library. You will see the purchased track.</li><li>These audiobooks from iTunes Store have .m4b file extension, and can be played on iTunes and iPod Shuffle with the bookmark resume-play feature.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Audiobooks from audible.com </p><br><br>www.audible.com also sells audiobooks. All these are iTunes-and-iPod compatible.<br><br>To purchase from this site;<br><br><ul><li>Create an Audible account and then buy online.</li><li>Windows users need to download and install Audible Manager, a simple software from Audible. Use this software to download Audible audiobook files into iTunes.Mac users are luckier – their Audible files download directly into iTunes.</li></ul>All audiobooks downloaded from audible.com are in .AA file format and offer the same bookmark resume-play feature as audiobooks from iTunes Store.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Transferring audiobooks to your iPod Shuffle </p><br><br>Audiobooks have to be loaded manually onto your iPod Shuffle.<br><br>To do this:<br><br><ul><li>Make sure your Shuffle is connected to the computer, and iTunes is open.</li><li>Click on Audiobooks under Library.</li><li>Select your audiobooks.</li><li>Drag your selection onto the iPod Shuffle icon in the Source List.</li><li>Wait till your iPod syncing is over.</li><li>Now, click on iPod Shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>You find the Audiobooks have been loaded onto your Shuffle.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Play audiobooks on iPod Shuffle</p><br><br>To play an audiobook;<br><br><ul><li>Press the Play / Pause button.</li><li>Press the Next / Fast-forward button once to skip to the next chapter.</li><li>Press and hold the Next / Fast-forward button to fast-forward through the current chapter.</li><li>Press and hold the Previous / Rewind button to rewind through the current chapter.</li><li>Press the Previous / Rewind button once to skip to the beginning of the current chapter.</li><li>Press the Previous / Rewind button twice to skip to the previous chapter.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='21'>
    <chaptername>How to prevent iTunes from opening Automatically.</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>PREVENTING iTUNES FROM OPENING AUTOMATICALLY</b></p><br><br> <p class='bodyText'>To prevent iTunes from opening automatically;<br><br><ul><li>Connect your iPod shuffle to the computer.</li><li>iTunes opens automatically.</li><li>Select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Scroll down to Options.</li><li>Deselect "Open iTunes when this iPod is connected."</li><li>Click Apply.</li><li>Now when you connect your Shuffle, iTunes will not open automatically.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='22'>
    <chaptername>How to organise your audio with iTunes - Create, modify and delete playlists and Smart playlists</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>ORGANIZE YOUR AUDIO WITH iTUNES</b></p><br><br><p class='headingText'>Playlist</p><br><br><p class='headingText'>Create your Playlist</p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>A playlist, in iTunes, is a compilation of your choice.<br><br>Using iTunes, you can organize songs and other items into playlists, in any way you want.<br><br>To make a playlist in iTunes;<br><br><ul><li>From the iTunes menu, select File and New Playlist.</li><li>Or click the Add button – that is, Create a playlist button – at the bottom.</li><li>Type a name for the playlist.</li><li>Click Music under Library.</li><li>Select a song or other item.</li><li>To select multiple songs, hold down the Shift key or the Command key on a Mac computer as you click each song.</li><li>To do the same on a Windows PC, press the Shift key or the Control key while selecting.</li><li>Drag the selection to the playlist.</li><li>The new playlist is created.</li><li>You can make as many playlists as you like, using any of the songs in your iTunes library.</li></ul><br><br>When multiple songs are selected, you can quickly create a playlist from these.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>In iTunes, click Music under Library.</li><li>Select the music tracks.</li><li>From the iTunes menu, select File and New Playlist from Selection.</li><li>Type a name for the Playlist.</li><li>The new playlist is created.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Modify your Playlist</p><br><br>Add music to your playlist:<br><br><ul><li>In iTunes, click Music under Library.</li><li>Select a single item, or multiple items using the Shift key.</li><li>Drag the selection to the playlist where you want the music or songs to be added.</li><li>Now, click on the playlist.</li><li>The new music or songs have been added, and appear at the end of the list.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Remove music from your playlist</p><ul><li>Click on the playlist to see its contents.</li><li>Select a single item, or multiple items with the Shift key.</li><li>Press the Delete key on your keyboard.</li><li>A message appears, asking for a confirmation.</li><li>Click on the Remove button to delete the selection from the playlist.</li><li>The selected items are deleted from the Playlist.</li></ul><br><br>However, deleting an item from a playlist, doesn’t remove it from your iTunes library.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Delete your playlist</p><br><br>You can delete a playlist from iTunes.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Click on the playlist name under PLAYLISTS in iTunes.</li><li>The playlist is selected.</li><li>Press the Delete key on your keyboard.</li><li>Now, click on the Delete button.</li><li>The playlist is removed from the Source List.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'><b>SMART PLAYLIST</b></p><br><br><p class='headingText'>Create Smart Playlist</p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>A Smart Playlist, in iTunes, is a playlist which contains items – songs, audiobooks etc – that match some specific rules set by you.<br><br>To make a Smart Playlist;<br><br><ul><li>From iTunes menu, select File and New Smart Playlist.</li><li>Make sure the “Match the following rule” check box is selected.</li><li>Also make sure the “Live Update” check box is selected. It enables iTunes to update this playlist whenever items in your iTunes Library are added, removed or changed.</li><li>Now, for example, you may want to create a playlist of songs by a particular artist.</li><li>Select Artist from the first drop-down menu.</li><li>From the middle drop-down menu, select "contains".</li><li>Type your favorite artist’s name in the input box on the right.</li><li>Select the “Limit to” check box.</li><li>Type 5 in the number input box.</li><li>Select album from the “selected by” drop-down menu.</li><li>Click OK.</li><li>Your Smart Playlist is created with a gear icon.</li><li>Now, whenever you import a new CD from that artist into iTunes, the first five songs of that album will be added automatically to the Smart Playlist.</li><li>Now, import a CD of that artist into iTunes Library.</li><li>If iTunes automatically asks for import when you insert the CD, click on the Yes button.</li><li>When importing is over, click on the new Smart Playlist you have created under PLAYLISTS.</li><li>The content window shows the first five songs have automatically been added to the Smart Playlist.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Modify Smart Playlist</p><br><br>You can also modify your Smart Playlist.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Click on the Smart Playlist name.</li><li>From the File menu, select Edit Smart Playlist.</li><li>The Smart Playlist window opens up.</li><li>If you want to add another rule for this Smart Playlist, click on the + button at the extreme right.</li><li>You can add your new rule – using the drop-down menus and the input box in the same way as you’ve done earlier.</li><li>Click OK when you have finished.</li><li>Now, iTunes will update this Smart Playlist with the new rules.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='23'>
    <chaptername>How to Autofill music and how to  Autofill only checked items</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>AUTOFILL THE MUSIC ON iPod SHUFFLE</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>You can set how music will be loaded from iTunes onto iPod Shuffle by configuring options at the bottom of the Shuffle contents window.<br><br>With Autofill, iTunes can automatically load a selection of your songs onto iPod shuffle with the click of a button.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Autofill generally</p><br><br>To autofill your Shuffle;<br><br><ul><li>Select iPod Shuffle in the Source Pane.</li><li>Check the playlist you want to autofill – from the pop-up “Autofill From” menu.</li><li>Or if you wish to autofill music from your entire library – choose Music.</li><li>You will get three options to choose from.<ol><li>Choose items randomly – If it is selected, iTunes will shuffle the order of songs while transferring them onto iPod shuffle.<br><br>Deselect this, so that, iTunes transfers songs in the order they appear in your library or selected playlist.</li><li>Choose higher rated items more often – If it is selected, iTunes will autofill the songs you listen to most.</li><li>Replace all items when Autofilling – when deselected, iTunes will add additional songs in the available space of your Shuffle.<br><br>Select this option for now.  iTunes will then replace the existing songs on iPod shuffle with the new songs you’ve chosen. The older songs on your Shuffle will be removed. </li></ol></li><li>Click Autofill.</li><li>The status bar shows how the autofill is progressing.</li><li>When the autofill is done, a message says "iPod sync is complete."</li><li>Check your iPod Shuffle. Its earlier contents have been completely replaced by the new playlist songs.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Autofill only checked items</p><br><br>You can limit autofill to checked items, so that iTunes will autofill only items that are selected in your iTunes library.<br><br>Items that you’ve deselected will be ignored.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Select iPod shuffle in the iTunes Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Scroll down – and select "Sync only checked songs."</li><li>Click Apply.</li><li>Now, click on any playlist under PLAYLIST.</li><li>Select the songs you wish to transfer to your Shuffle.</li><li>Make sure the remaining songs are deselected.</li><li>Click on the iPod Shuffle icon in the Source List</li><li>Click the Contents tab.</li><li>Select the playlist you have modified from the Autofill From pop-up menuw.</li><li>Make sure the “Replace all items when Autofilling” option is deselected.</li><li>Click on Autofill.</li><li>The selected songs from the playlist are added to your iPod Shuffle contents.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='24'>
    <chaptername>How to order the music in your Shuffle using iTunes</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>ARRANGE THE ORDER OF MUSIC ON iPod SHUFFLE</b></p><br><br> <p class='bodyText'>Once songs are loaded onto iPod shuffle, you can rearrange their order with iTunes.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>In iTunes, select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the header above the first column to arrange the tracks by number.</li><li>Click again to arrange the tracks in reverse order.</li><li>Drag the songs upward or downward – and change the order of the songs as you wish.</li><li>Your songs are set accordingly.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='25'>
    <chaptername>How to use your Shuffle as an external storage device - copy and delete data from your shuffle</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>USING iPod SHUFFLE AS AN EXTERNAL DISK</b></p><br><br> <p class='bodyText'>You can store and manage data files on iPod shuffle just as you would on your computer disk drives. For this, you need to enable your Shuffle as an external disk.<br><br>Remember, you must eject your iPod Shuffle before disconnecting it from the computer after disk usage.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Copy data files from your computer to the Shuffle</p><br><br>To copy data files from your computer to the iPod Shuffle;<br><br><ul><li>Make sure your iPod shuffle is connected to your computer, and iTunes is open.</li><li>Select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Go to the Options section and select "Enable disk use."</li><li>You may need to scroll down to see the disk settings.</li><li>Adjust the slider – and set how much space should be reserved for songs versus data.</li><li>Click Apply.</li><li>If you are a Mac user, you will find the iPod shuffle disk icon appearing on the desktop.<ol><li>Open the Finder.</li><li>Select the files you want to transfer.</li><li>Drag the files to your iPod shuffle icon.</li></ol></li><li>If you are a Windows PC user, click on My Computer.<ol><li>You will find the iPod shuffle disk icon appearing as the next available drive letter.</li><li>Open Windows Explorer.</li><li>Select the files you want to transfer.</li><li>Drag the files to your iPod shuffle icon.</li></ol></li><li>Watch the status light on your iPod Shuffle. It’s blinking amber continuously. Now click the iPod Shuffle icon. The data files have been loaded onto your shuffle.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Delete data files from your iPod Shuffle </p><br><br>To remove any file from your iPod Shuffle;<br><br><ul><li>If you are a Mac user, open Finder.</li><li>If you are a Windows PC user, open My Computer.</li><li>Click on the iPod Shuffle disk icon.</li><li>The data files of your Shuffle will appear.</li><li>Select the files.</li><li>Press the Delete key on your keyboard.</li><li>A message box appears, click yes.</li><li>The files are deleted from your iPod Shuffle.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Copy data files from your Shuffle to any other computer</p><br><br><ul><li>Connect your Shuffle to the USB 2.0 port of the other computer.</li><li>If iTunes open automatically, a message appears, asking if you want to sync the iPod Shuffle with the iTunes library on the new computer.</li><li>Click Cancel to retain the music content of your iPod shuffle.</li><li>If you are a Mac user, open Finder.</li><li>If you are a Windows PC user, open My Computer.</li><li>Click on the iPod Shuffle disk icon.</li><li>You will find the data files stored on your Shuffle.</li><li>Select the files.</li><li>Drag these files from iPod shuffle to a drive on the new computer.</li><li>The files are transferred to the new computer.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Things to remember</p><br><br><ul><li>iPod shuffle is formatted as a FAT-32 volume, which is supported by both Macs and PCs. This allows you to use iPod shuffle to transfer files between computers with different operating systems.</li><li>You cannot play audio files that you copy to iPod shuffle using the Macintosh Finder or Windows Explorer.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='26'>
    <chaptername>How to set the volume on your Shuffle using iTunes</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>VOLUME SETTINGS OF SHUFFLE USING iTUNES</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>Sometimes, the volume of songs and other audio may vary depending on how the audio was recorded or encoded. In such cases, you may want iTunes to adjust the volume automatically, so they play at the same relative volume level.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Set iTunes to play music at same sound level</p><br><br>At first, you set iTunes to play the music or songs at the same sound level.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Make sure iTunes is open.</li><li>If you are using a Mac, choose iTunes and select Preferences.</li><li>If you are using a Windows PC, choose Edit and select Preferences.</li><li>Click Playback.</li><li>Select Sound Check.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>iPod shuffle to use the iTunes volume settings</p><br><br>You can set your iPod shuffle to use the iTunes volume settings.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Make sure your iPod Shuffle is connected to the computer and iTunes is open.</li><li>Select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Scroll down to go to Options.</li><li>Select Enable Sound Check.</li><li>Click Apply.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Setting a volume limit</p><br><br>You can set a limit for the volume on iPod shuffle through iTunes.<br><br>To limit maximum volume for your Shuffle:<br><br><ul><li>In iTunes, select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Scroll down to go to Options.</li><li>Select "Limit maximum volume."</li><li>Drag the slider to the desired maximum volume.</li><li>Click Apply.<br><br>Now, when you Increase the volume of your, and the status light blinks amber three times, that means you are trying to increase the volume beyond the limit set in iTunes.</li></ul><br><br>You may now want to prevent this volume setting from being changed by someone else. So, you can set a password in iTunes.<br><br>To set a password,<br><br><ul><li>Click the open lock icon.</li><li>Enter a password.</li><li>Enter it again to verify your password.</li><li>Click OK.</li><li>The password is set.</li><li>You can now see the lock icon.</li></ul><br><br>You can change or remove the volume limit.<br><br>For this you have to enter the password you've set.<br><br><ul><li>Click Apply when you finish your setting.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Deselect maximum volume limit</p><br><br>You can remove the volume limit of your iPod Shuffle through iTunes.<br><br>To remove the volume limit,<br><br><ul><li>In iTunes, select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Scroll down to Options.</li><li>The "Limit maximum volume" option is not activated, because it is password protected.</li><li>Click on the lock icon.</li><li>Enter your password and click OK.</li><li>The lock opens and the "Limit maximum volume" option is activated.</li><li>Deselect "Limit maximum volume."</li><li>Click Apply.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='27'>
    <chaptername>How to disable and reenable the iPod Shuffle buttons</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>DISABLING & ENABLING THE iPod SHUFFLE BUTTONS</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>You can disable the buttons on iPod shuffle so that nothing happens if they are pressed accidentally.<br><br>To disable the iPod shuffle buttons;<br><br><ul><li>Press and hold the Play / Pause button for three seconds.</li><li>The status light glows green, and then blinks orange three times.</li><li>The buttons become disabled.</li><li>If you press a button now, the status light simply blinks orange once. No button of your iPod Shuffle works now.</li></ul><br><br>To re-enable the buttons;<br><br><ul><li>Press and hold the Play / Pause for three seconds.</li><li>The status light glows orange, and then blinks green three times.</li><li>The buttons become enabled.</li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='28'>
    <chaptername>Audio File formats support and not supported by iPod shuffle and how to convert tracks to 128 kbps AAC files while loading</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>AUDIO FILE FORMATS</b></p><br><br><p class='headingText'>File formats supported by iPod Shuffle</p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>It is very important to know the audio file formats supported by iPod shuffle.<br><br>The formats are, AAC (M4A, M4B, M4P) (up to 320 Kbps), MP3 (up to 320 Kbps), MP3 Variable Bit Rate (VBR), WAV, AA (audible.com spoken word, formats 2, 3, and 4).<br><br><p class='headingText'>File formats not supported by iPod Shuffle</p><br><br>iPod shuffle does not support AIFF, Apple Lossless, MPEG Layer 1, MPEG Layer 2 audio files, WMA, or audible.com format 1 audio files.<br><br><p class='headingText'>Converting music to 128 kbps AAC file while loading onto iPod Shuffle</p><br><br>When you've imported higher bit rate song files, such as AIFF files, into iTunes, you can convert them to 128 kbps .AAC files while loading them onto your iPod Shuffle.<br><br>This way you can reduce each song file size and fit more songs to your iPod Shuffle<br><br>This does not affect the quality or size of the songs in iTunes.<br><br>To do this;<br><br><ul><li>Select a song in iTunes Library.</li><li>From File menu, choose Get Info. The music file properties are displayed.</li><li>Check whether the song file has a higher bit rate.</li><li>Click OK.</li><li>Now, in iTunes, select iPod shuffle in the Source List.</li><li>Click the Settings tab.</li><li>Scroll down to Options.</li><li>Select "Convert higher bit rate songs to 128 kbps AAC".</li><li>Click Apply.</li><li>Watch the iPod update message.</li><li>With this setting, iTunes will henceforth convert songs to 128 kbps AAC files while they are being transferred onto iPod shuffle.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Things to remember</p><br><br>A song encoded using AAC or MP3 format has near CD-quality sound, but takes up much less space than a song encoded using AIFF or WAV format.<br><br>When you import music from a CD using iTunes, it is converted to AAC format by default.<br><br>Using iTunes for Windows, you can convert non-protected WMA files to AAC or MP3 format. This can be useful if you have a library of music encoded in WMA format.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='29'>
    <chaptername>How to trouble shoot your iPod shuffle - Reset, Retry, Restart, Reinstall, Restore</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>TIPS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'>Here... we will discuss some tips and troubleshooting methods of your iPod Shuffle...<br><br><p class='headingText'>The five Rs for iPod Shuffle</p><br><br><ul><li>Most problems with your iPod can be solved with one of the 5 R's.</li><li>The 5 R's are<br><br><ol><li>Reset</li><li>Retry</li><li>Restart</li><li>Reinstall</li><li>Restore</li></ol></li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Reset</p><br><br>To reset your iPod shuffle,<br><br><ul><li>Eject your iPod shuffle from iTunes, if connected.</li><li>Remove iPod shuffle from the USB port.</li><li>	Slide the switch on the back of iPod shuffle to the OFF position.</li><li>Wait for 5 seconds.</li><li>Slide the same switch to turn on the shuffle.</li><li>iPod shuffle is now reset.</li><li>After resetting iPod shuffle, if you are going to attach it to your computer, make sure the shuffle is switched off.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Retry</p><br><br>Suppose... when you connect your iPod to your computer... you cannot see the iPod icon in iTunes.<br><br>Then, you can retry with a different USB port of your computer.<br><br><ul><li>Detach the USB cable from its existing port.</li><li>Connect it to another port.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Restart</p><br><br>Some problems with your iPod may be solved by simply restarting your computer.<br><br><ul><li>Restart your computer.</li><li>Ensure that the latest software updates are installed.</li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Reinstall</p><br><br>Some iPod problems are solved if you reinstall the latest version of iTunes from the web.<br><br><ul><li>Go to http://www.apple.com/itunes/downloads<ul><li>Download and install the latest iTunes software</li></ul></li><li>Alternatively, check for iTunes software updates.</li><ul><li>Connect to the Internet.</li><li>In iTunes, select Help > Check for Updates.</li><li>A small window... with an animated progress bar... opens.<br><br>-It says, "Checking for updates".</li><br><br><li>If a new version is available, a dialog box appears<br><br>specifying the version, and<br><br>asking if you wish to download it now.</li><li>Click on "Download iTunes"</li><li>Then, follow on-screen instructions.</li></ul><li>Sometimes, you may be reinstalling the same version of iTunes.<br><br><ul><li>The iTunes installer may now ask whether you wish to Repair or Remove the software.</li><li>Choose Repair</li><li>This will fix damaged files, and help iTunes run better.</li><li>This will be faster than reinstalling iTunes all over again.</li></ul></li></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>Restore</p><br><br><ul><li>If the problem persists, you can use iTunes to update or restore your iPod software.<br><br>a) If you update<ul><li>the software is updated,</li><li>but your settings and songs are not affected.</li></ul></li><br><br>b) If you restore<ul><li>all data is erased from iPod.</li><li>all iPod settings are restored to their original state.</li></ul><li>To Update your iPod software<br><br><ul><li>Connect to the Internet.</li><li>Ensure that the latest version of iTunes is installed</li><li>Connect your iPod to your computer.</li><li>In iTunes, select iPod in the Source List.</li><li>Click Settings.</li><li>In the Version section, click Check for Update.</li><li>See whether your iPod</li></ul><br><ul><li>is up to date, or</li><li>needs a newer version of the software.</li><li>If it needs a newer version</li><li>You need to update to the latest version of the software.</li></ul></li><li>To Restore your iPod software<br><br><ul><li>Connect to the Internet.</li><li>Ensure that the latest version of iTunes is installed</li><li>Connect your iPod to your computer.</li><li>In iTunes, select iPod in the Source List.</li><li>Click Settings.</li><li>click Restore.</li><li>Follow onscreen instructions.</li></ul></li></ul></p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <chapter id='30'>
    <chaptername>What to do when your Suffle does not turn on or respond.</chaptername>
    <htmltext>
      <![CDATA[<p class='headingText'><b>WHEN YOUR iPod SHUFFLE WON'T TURN ON OR RESPOND, HERE ARE A FEW SUGGETIONS</b></p><br><br><p class='bodyText'><ul><ol><li>Check if the iPod Shuffle buttons are disabled.<br><br>If the status light blinks orange when you press a button, the iPod shuffle buttons are disabled.<br><br>To enable it again;Press and hold Play/Pause for about three seconds, until the status light blinks green.<br><br></li><li>Try connecting your iPod shuffle to a high-power USB port on your computer.</li><li>Your iPod shuffle battery may need to be recharged.</li><li>Try turning your iPod shuffle off, wait five seconds, and then turn it on again.</li><li>If nothing works, you may need to restore your iPod shuffle software.</li></ol></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>If iPod Shuffle isn't playing music</p><br><br>Make sure the earphones or headphone connector is pushed in all the way.<br><br>Make sure the volume is adjusted properly.<br><br>A volume limit may have been set.<br><br>Try pressing the Play / Pause button.<br><br>Your iPod shuffle might be in pause mode.<br><br><p class='headingText'>If you connect iPod Shuffle to your computer and nothing happens, here are some suggestions</p><br><br><ul><ol><li>Try to connect iPod shuffle to a different, high-power USB port on your computer.</li><li>iPod shuffle may need to be recharged.<ul><li>If there is no status light or the status light is dimmed and iPod shuffle doesn't appear in iTunes, the battery may be completely discharged.</li><li>Let your iPod shuffle charge for several minutes, and wait for it to come back to life.</li></ul></li><li>Make sure you have installed the latest iTunes software from Apple website.</li><li>Make sure your iPod shuffle is firmly seated in the dock.</li><li>Make sure the USB connector is oriented correctly. It can be inserted only one way.</li><li>The iPod shuffle might need to be reset.<br><br>To do this,<br><br>-Turn iPod shuffle off, wait five seconds, and then turn it back on again.</li><li>Make sure you have the required computer and software versions.</li><li>You can try restarting your computer.</li><li>If none of the previous suggestions solves the problem, you might need to restore iPod software.</li><li>If restoring iPod shuffle doesn't solve the problem, iPod shuffle may need to be repaired. For this, you can visit the Apple website for iPod shuffle service & support.</li></ol></ul><br><br><p class='headingText'>If audio files load slowly</p><br><br>Try to connect iPod shuffle to a USB 2.0 port on your computer. USB 2.0 loads songs and data faster than USB 1.1.<br><br><p class='headingText'>If you can't load a song or other item onto iPod Shuffle</p><br><br>The song might have been encoded in a format that iPod shuffle doesn't support. <br><br>Please check the file format's compatibility.<br><br><p class='headingText'>If the chapters in an audio-book play out of order</p><br><br>Make sure the shuffle switch on iPod shuffle is set to repeat, so that the chapters of the audiobook play in order.<br><br>If the chapters were added to iPod shuffle out of order, connect iPod shuffle to your computer<br><br>In iTunes, select iPod shuffle in the Source List.<br><br>You can now, using iTunes, rearrange the tracks.</p>]]>
    </htmltext>
  </chapter>
  <breadcrumbs>
    <![CDATA[You are here :  Apple > Personal Entertainment >  iPod Shuffle 2nd Gen]]>
  </breadcrumbs>
  <productname>iPod Shuffle 2nd Gen</productname>
</main>